HAMMAD HASSAN

Birmingham, United Kingdom 07554830329 - hammad.hsn7991@gmail.com

Permit: International | **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/hammad-hassan-51567b29

Portfolio: https://hammad7991-portfolio.netlify.app/ | https://github.com/HammadHassan7991

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a Full Stack Developer with 2 years of experience, I possess significant proficiency in front-end and back-end development using React, Next.js, Node.js, and Javascript. Driven by an unwavering passion for web development, I am committed to working in a stimulating and challenging environment that fosters continuous learning and skills enhancement. I am enthusiastic about contributing my expertise towards achieving the company's growth objectives and making a meaningful impact in the industry.

WORK HISTORY

08/2022 - 09/2023

Full Stack Developer

Tripsheperd - Canada

Develop and maintain the company's internal admin system. Leveraging my expertise in React, along with GraphQl queries integrated with Hasura Postgres. Developed a fully optimized company's tour booking website using Next.js including stripe payment integration. Proficiently incorporated Google Maps API to create location-based features within applications, enabling functionalities such as geolocation and mapping. Write unit test codes using Mocha & Jest, and contributed to the development and maintenance of databases, ensuring that they were secure, scalable, and efficient. Further implemented features are:

- Authentication using JWT, Next Auth0, validation, assigned multiple user roles, and authorization.
- Integration of headless CMS Strapi with database using remote schemas.
- Cross-site protection using CSFR token and SSL encryption.
- Integration with third-party booking service providers to keep records of external bookings (third-party APIs integration).
- Integration with Google Analytics for payment tracking and SEO optimization purposes

01/2021 - 02/2022

Front-End Developer

Secure Residence Pvt Ltd - Islamabad

Developed and maintained the company's real estate web application using React and Sass for performance and cross-browser compatibility. Integrated third-party APIs for appointment scheduling system enabling users to book property viewings. I also write unit test cases using Mocha-Chai to ensure code quality. Further implemente features are:

- Developed scalable backend REST APIs to get available slots for booking.
- Developed and maintained chatbots with real-time customer service interaction capabilities using Socket.io, enhancing user engagement and providing immediate assistance."

05/2020 - 11/2020

Front-End Developer

Freelancing - Pakistan

Developed web applications, leveraging cutting-edge technology to enhance user experience. One of my notable projects includes a web application for a gym Management System where users can track their fitness progress and access personalized workout routines. Implemented a dynamic class scheduling feature enabling members to view and sign up for fitness classes offered by the gym. I used Javascript frameworks and libraries such as React, Redux, and firebase to create cross-platform solutions that exceeded user experience

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- Javascript, Python, Typescript, HTML.
- React, Next.js, Node.js, Redux, Redux-Toolkit, Redux-Saga.
- SQL, GraphQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Hasura
- Tailwind, CSS, Sass
- Dockers, Git/Github, Jira, Taskade

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

- NodeJS The Complete Guide (MVC, REST APIs, MongoDB) By Maximilian Schwarzmüller, Udemy.
- Master the (Data Structures + Algorithms) by Andrei Neagoie, Udemy.
- Complete React Developer in 2023 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL) by Andrei Neagoie, Udemy

EDUCATION

09/2023 - Current Master of Science: Data Analytics

Aston University - Birmingham, BIR

09/2015 - 08/2019 Bachelor of Science: Telecommunication

Hitec University Taxila - Pakistan

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu/Hindi